Register of the A. (Andrei) Siniavskii Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1959-1998., See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/Prison writings/Correspondence; DONAT SINIAVSKII FILE/Correspondence; EVDOKIIA-TORKHOVA SINIAVSKAIA FILE/Correspondence; and SINTAKSIS FILE/Correspondence
  - Radio Danemark (Ole Vesterholt), 1977 (Folder 10: 62)
  - Radio France Internationale, 1996 (Folder 10: 63)
  - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 1974-1990 (Folder 10: 64)
  - Radio Liberty Committee, 1975., See also SUBJECT FILE/Radio Liberty (Folder 10: 65)
  - Radio Notre Dame, 1991 (Folder 10: 66)
  - Radygin, Anatolii, n.d. (Folder 10: 67)
  - Rancour-Laferrière, Daniel, 1986 (Folder 10: 68)
  - Rapetti, Sergio, 1976-1980 (Folder 10: 69)
  - Rawicz, Piotr, 1973 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Rebers, Abraham, 1974-1975 (Folder 11: 2)
  - Reddaway, Peter, 1979-1981 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Reiman, Mikhail, 1985 (Folder 11: 4)
  - Reve, Karl van het, 1981-1984 (Folder 11: 5)
  - RIAS Berlin Rundfunkanstalt (Barbara Wahlster), 1990 (Folder 11: 6)
  - Rovner, Arkadii, 1987 (Folder 11: 7)
  - Rozanova, Mariia., See SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/Prison writings
  - Rubinstein, Natal'ia, 1976 (Folder 11: 8)
  - Ruge, Elizabeth, 1994 (Folder 11: 9)
  - Rusak, Vladimir, 1983 (Folder 11: 10)
  - Russia (Federation), Posol'stvo (France), 1994 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Outside of Russia, 1974 (Folder 11: 12)
  - Russkaia mysl' (Zinaida Shakhovskaia), 1974-1981 (Folder 11: 13)
  - Russkaia rech', 1990 (Folder 11: 14)
  - S. Fischer Verlag, 1985-1987 (Folder 11: 15)
  - Samarin, Vladimir, 1973-1975 (Folder 11: 16)
  - San Vicente, Ricardo, 1983-1990 (Folder 11: 17)
  - Scammell, Michael, 1980-1985 (Folder 11: 18)
  - Schlögel, Karl, 1979 (Folder 11: 19)
  - Science Fiction Studies, 1977 (Folder 11: 20)
  - Scottish Slavonic Review, University of Glasgow, 1983 (Folder 11: 21)
  - Shahovskoy, John, Archbishop, 1973-1979 (Folder 11: 22)
  - Shifrin, Avraham, 1975 (Folder 11: 23)
  - Shmaina-Velikanova, Anna, 1990 (Folder 11: 24)
  - Shragin, Boris, 1980., See also SUBJECT FILE/Shragin, Boris (Folder 11: 25)
  - Shtromas, A., 1976-1980 (Folder 11: 26)
  - Stern, 1977 (Folder 11: 27)
  - Sih, Julia Junzhi Xue, 1990-1995 (Folder 11: 28)
  - Silver Age Publishing (Grigorii Polak), n.d. (Folder 11: 29)
  - Slonim, Mark, 1974-1976 (Folder 11: 30)
  - Soloviev, Vladimir, 1979 (Folder 11: 31)
  - Souvarine, Boris, 1974 (Folder 11: 32)
  - Stanford University, Department of Slavic Languages and Literatures (Irina Shevelenko and Andrei Ustinov), 1993 (Folder 11: 33)
  - Stolypin, Arkadii, 1973-1974 (Folder 11: 34)
  - Sugiyama, Haruko, 1984 (Folder 11: 35)
  - Super, Sasha, n.d. (Folder 11: 36)
  - Syzranskii gorodskoi kraevedcheskii muzei, 1990 (Folder 11: 37)
  - Tarasova, Natalia, 1974 (Folder 11: 38)
  - Tatischeff, S., 1974-1983 (Folder 11: 39)
  - Teatral'naia Zhizn', 1989 (Folder 11: 40)
  - Thames Television PLC, 1990 (Folder 11: 41)
  - Tikos, Laszlo, 1973-1974 (Folder 11: 42)
  - Time Magazine, 1989 (Folder 11: 43)
  - Titova, Emma, 1974 (Folder 11: 44)
  - Tribune socialiste, 1977 (Folder 11: 45)
  - Turchin, (?), n.d. (Folder 11: 46)
  - Turin, Valentin, 1980 (Folder 11: 47)
  - Udodov, Aleksandr, 1975-1979 (Folder 11: 48)
  - Uggla, Claes-Goran, 1976-1977 (Folder 11: 49)
  - Unione Cattolica Stampa Italiana, 1985 (Folder 11: 50)
  - Università Degli Studi, Venice (Vittorio Strada), 1974 (Folder 11: 51)
  - Universität Bremen, Forschungsstelle Osteuropa (Dietrich Beyrau), 1984-1986 (Folder 11: 52)
  - Université de Genève, 1994 (Folder 11: 53)
  - Université de Paris-Sorbonne, 1976-1977 (Folder 11: 54)
  - Universiteit van Amsterdam, 1980-1987 (Folder 11: 55)
  - Universitetet I Oslo, 1974-1975. (Folder 11: 56)
    Includes program and material re trip to Norway
  - University of Alberta, 1985 (Folder 11: 57)
  - University of British Columbia, 1980 (Folder 11: 58)
  - University of London, School of Slavonic and East European Studies, 1973-1989. (Folder 11: 59)
    Includes contract for contribution to Ideology in Russian Literature
  - University of Oregon, 1996 (Folder 11: 60)
  - University of Ottowa (Nikolai Pervushin), 1975 (Folder 11: 61)
  - University of Southern California, 1983 (Folder 11: 62)
  - University of Washington, 1979 (Folder 11: 63)
  - Utimura, Goske, 1984-1985 (Folder 11: 64)
  - Vagin, Evgenii, 1967-1980 (Folder 11: 65)
  - Venclova, Tomas, 1980-1983 (Folder 11: 66)
  - Vernik, Igor, Rev., 1973 (Folder 11: 67)
  - Viking Press (Annabel Huxley), 1990 (Folder 11: 68)
  - Vishniak, Vladimir, 1981 (Folder 11: 69)
  - Voennaia, Inna, 1989 (Folder 11: 70)
  - Vogt, Johan (Norwegian P.E.N. Club), 1975 (Folder 11: 71)
  - Volkov, Solomon, 1981 (Folder 11: 72)
  - Vserossiiskaia Gosudarstvennaia Biblioteka Inostrannoi Literatury (L. Khotin), 1993 (Folder 11: 73)
  - Weidle, Vladimir, 1973-1975 (Folder 11: 74)
  - Wiez, 1994 (Folder 11: 75)
  - Zamoiska, Hélène, 1973-1976. (Folder 11: 76)
    Includes typescript with encripted message, 1973
  - ZED Books, 1990 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Zernov, Nikolai, 1974 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Zholkovskii, Aleksandr, 1985-1988 (Folder 12: 3)
  - Zhuk, Viktor, 1991-1992 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Zilberberg, Ilya, 1974-1981 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Zuckermann, A., 1989 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Zveteremich, Pietro, 1974-1981 (Folder 12: 7)
- UNIVERSITY LECTURES, n.d.
  Lectures delivered at the University of Paris-Sorbonne. Holographs unless otherwise noted
  - Akhmatova, Anna
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 12: 8-9)
      Notes and photocopies
    - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 12: 10)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 12: 11)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 12: 12)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 12: 13)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 12: 14)
  - Babel', Isaac.
    Also includes material re Dmitrii Furmanov
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 12: 15)
    - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 12: 16)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 12: 17)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 12: 18)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Box-folder 13: 1)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 13: 2)
  - Bal'mont, Konstantin
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 13: 3)
    - Texts
      - Nos. 2-3 (Folder 13: 4)
      - Nos. 4-5 (Folder 13: 5)
      - Nos. 6-7 (Folder 13: 6)
      - Nos. 8-9 (Folder 13: 7)
      - Nos. 10-11 (Folder 13: 8)
      - Nos. 12-13 (Folder 13: 9)
  - Benediktov, Vladimir (Box 14)
    - Preparatory material.
      Photocopies
    - Texts (Folder 14: 1)
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 14: 2)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 14: 3)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 14: 4)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 14: 5)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 14: 6)
      - Nos. 11-13 (Folder 14: 7)
  - Blok, Aleksandr
    - Preparatory material (Folder 14: 8)
    - Texts
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 14: 9)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 14: 10)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 14: 11)
      - Nos. 12-13 (Folder 14: 12)
      - Nos. 14-15 (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - Nos. 16-17 (Folder 15: 2)
      - Nos. 18-19 (Folder 15: 3)
      - Nos. 20-21 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Esenin, Sergei - Texts
    - General
      - Nos. 1-2. (Folder 15: 5)
        Also appears as chapter of "Russkaia poeziia XX veka"
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 15: 6)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 15: 7)
      - Nos. 7-9 (Folder 15: 8)
      - Nos. 10-11 (Folder 15: 9)
      - Nos. 12-13 (Folder 15: 10)
      - Nos. 14-16 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - "Chernyi chelovek" (Folder 16: 2)
    - "Pugachev" (Folder 16: 3)
  - Futurism - Preparatory material. (Folder 16: 4)
  - Gippius, Zinaida
    - Preparatory material (Folder 16: 5)
    - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 16: 6)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 16: 7)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 16: 8)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 16: 9)
  - Gumilev, Nikolai - Preparatory material (Folder 16: 10)
  - Khlebnikov, Velimir - Lecture No. 8 (Folder 16: 11)
  - Khodasevich, Vladislav - Text of Nekropol'
    - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 16: 12)
    - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 16: 13)
    - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 16: 14)
    - No. 7 (Folder 16: 15)
  - Kolkhoz literature (Kolkhoznaia literatura) - Texts (Box 17)
    - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 17: 1)
    - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 17: 2)
    - No. 5 (Folder 17: 3)
  - Kuzmin, Mikhail
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 17: 4)
    - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 17: 5)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 17: 6)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 17: 7)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 17: 8)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 17: 9)
  - Leskov, Nikolai
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 18: 1-2)
    - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 18: 3)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 18: 4)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 18: 5)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 18: 6)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 18: 7)
      - Nos. 11-12 (Folder 18: 8)
      - Nos. 13-14 (Folder 18: 9)
      - Nos. 15-16 (Folder 18: 10)
      - Nos. 17-18 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - Nos. 19-20 (Folder 19: 2)
  - Maiakovskii, Vladimir
    - Plays - "Klop i Bania"
      - Research material (Folder 19: 3-5)
      - Texts
        - Nos. 1-4 (Folder 19: 6)
        - Nos. 5-10 (Folder 19: 7)
        - Nos. 11-17 (Folder 19: 8)
    - Poetry - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 19: 9)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 19: 10)
      - Nos. 5-6, 8 (Folder 19: 11)
      - Nos. 12-13 (Folder 19: 12)
      - Nos. 14-16 (Box-folder 20: 1)
      - Nos. 17-18 (Folder 20: 2)
      - Nos. 19-20 (Folder 20: 3)
      - Nos. 21-22 (Folder 20: 4)
      - Nos. 23-24 (Folder 20: 5)
  - Old Russian culture (Drevne-russkaia kul'tura)
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 20: 6-10)
      Notes
    - Texts (Box 21)
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 21: 1)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 21: 2)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 21: 3)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 21: 4)
      - Nos. 10-11 (Folder 21: 5)
      - Nos. 12-13 (Folder 21: 6)
      - Nos. 14-15 (Folder 21: 7)
      - Nos. 16-18 (Folder 21: 8)
      - Miscellaneous texts of lectures on Old Russian culture delivered on other occasions (Folder 21: 9)
  - Pasternak, Boris - Texts
    - General (Folder 21: 10)
    - Doktor Zhivago (Folder 21: 11)
  - Rozanov, Vasilii (Box 22)
    - Drafts of lectures (Folder 22: 1-5)
    - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 22: 6)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 22: 7)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 22: 8)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 22: 9)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 22: 10)
      - Nos. 11-12 (Folder 22: 11)
      - Nos. 13-14 (Folder 22: 12)
      - Nos. 15-16 (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - Nos. 17-18 (Folder 23: 2)
      - Nos. 19-20 (Folder 23: 3)
  - Russian culture from 1905-1917 (Russkaia kul'tura v period 1905-1917 godov)
    - Research material. (Folder 23: 4)
    - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 23: 5)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 23: 6)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 23: 7)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 23: 8)
      - Nos. 9-11 (Folder 23: 9)
  - Russian culture of the 1860s (Russkaia kul'tura 60'kh godov)
    - Reading list (Folder 23: 10)
    - Texts
      - No. 1 (Folder 23: 11)
      - Nos. 2-3 (Folder 23: 12)
      - Nos. 4-5 (Box-folder 24: 1)
      - Nos. 6-7 (Folder 24: 2)
      - Nos. 8-10 (Folder 24: 3)
  - Russian poetry of the early 20th century (Russkaia poeziia nachala XX veka)
    - Handouts for students (Folder 24: 4)
    - Outline for course (Folder 24: 5)
    - Preparatory material
      - Esenin, Sergei (Folder 24: 6)
      - Mandel'shtam, Osip (Folder 24: 7-8)
    - Texts (Box 25)
      - General
        - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 25: 1)
        - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 25: 2)
        - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 25: 3)
        - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 25: 4)
        - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 25: 5)
      - Tsvetaeva, Marina (Folder 25: 6)
  - Russian popular culture (Russkaia narodnaia kul'tura)
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 25: 7-10)
      Photocopies of texts
    - Texts (Box 26)
      - Part I
        - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 26: 1)
        - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 26: 2)
        - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 26: 3)
        - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 26: 4)
        - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 26: 5)
        - Nos. 11-12 (Folder 26: 6)
        - Additional material (Folder 26: 7)
      - Part II
        - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 26: 8)
        - Nos. 3-4 (Box-folder 27: 1)
        - Nos. 8-9 (Folder 27: 2)
        - Nos. 10-11 (Folder 27: 3)
  - Russian religious sects (Russkie religioznye sekty) - Text (Folder 27: 4)
  - Socialist realism (Sotsrealizm). Texts
    - General (Folder 27: 5-6)
    - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 27: 7)
    - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 27: 8)
    - Nos. 6-7 (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - Nos. 8-9 (Folder 28: 2)
    - Nos. 10-11 (Folder 28: 3)
  - Soviet civilization (Sovetskaia tsivilizatsiia)
    - Outline for course (Folder 28: 4)
    - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 28: 5)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 28: 6)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 28: 7)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Box-folder 29: 1)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 29: 2)
      - Nos. 11-12 (Folder 29: 3)
      - Nos. 13-14 (Folder 29: 4)
      - Nos. 15-16 (Folder 29: 5)
      - Nos. 17-18 (Folder 29: 6)
      - Nos. 19-20 (Folder 29: 7)
      - No. 21 (Folder 29: 8)
  - Soviet culture during the NEP (Sovetskaia kul'tura epokhi NEP'a) (Box 30)
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 30: 1)
    - Texts (Folder 30: 2-3)
  - Soviet culture from 1945-1953 (Sovetskaia kul'tura 1945-1953) - Texts
    - No. 1 (Folder 30: 4)
    - Nos. 2-3 (Folder 30: 5)
    - Nos. 4-5 (Folder 30: 6)
    - Nos. 6-7 (Folder 30: 7)
  - Tsvetaeva, Marina
    - Preparatory material
      - Correspondence. (Folder 30: 8)
        Photo and typescript copies
      - Writings. (Box-folder 31: 1-5)
        Handwritten and typescript copies, including samizdat versions
    - Texts
      - "Poeziia Mariny Tsvetaevoi."
        Also appears as Lecture 19 of Russian poetry of the early 20th century
        - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 31: 6)
        - No. 3 (Folder 31: 7)
        - Nos. 4-5 (Folder 31: 8)
        - Nos. 6-7 (Folder 31: 9)
        - Nos. 8-9 (Folder 31: 10)
        - Nos. 10-11 (Folder 31: 11)
        - Nos. 12-13 (Box-folder 32: 1)
        - Nos. 14-15 (Folder 32: 2)
        - Nos. 16-17 (Folder 32: 3)
        - Nos. 18-20 (Folder 32: 4)
      - "Proza Mariny Tsvetaevoi"
        - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 32: 5)
        - Nos. 4-5 (Folder 32: 6)
        - Nos. 6-7 (Folder 32: 7)
        - Nos. 8-9 (Folder 32: 8)
        - Nos. 10-11 (Folder 32: 9)
  - Tynianov, Iurii
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 32: 10)
    - Texts on "Smert' Vizir-Murata"
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 32: 11)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 32: 12)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 32: 13)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Box-folder 33: 1)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Folder 33: 2)
  - Zabolotskii, Nikolai - Lectures on "Stolbtsy"
    - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 33: 3)
    - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 33: 4)
    - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 33: 5)
  - Zamiatin, Evgenii - Preparatory material (Folder 33: 6)
  - Zoshchenko, Mikhail
    - Preparatory material. (Folder 33: 7)
      Notes and bibliography
    - Texts
      - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 33: 8)
      - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 33: 9)
      - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 33: 10)
      - Nos. 7-8 (Folder 33: 9)
      - Nos. 9-10 (Box-folder 34: 1)
      - Nos. 11-12 (Folder 34: 2)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1940's-1998
  - Creative writing and articles under the pseudonym of Abram Terts, arranged alphabetically., For reviews, see also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Articles about Andrei Siniavskii
    - Golos iz khora., See also AUDIO-VISUAL FILE/ Phonotapes/Siniavskii, Andrei
      - Typescript, 1971 (Folder 34: 3)
      - Reviews, 1974-1979 (Folder 34: 4)
    - "The Icicle," English translation in Encounter, 1962 February. (Folder 34: 5)
      Printed copy
    - Kroshka Tsores., See also SUBJECT FILE/Shragin, Boris
      - Holograph, n.d. (Folder 34: 6-7)
      - Notes, n.d. (Folder 34: 8)
      - Pasteup and imposition film for printing by "Vsia Moskva," 1991 (Folder 34: 9)
      - Reviews of French edition, André-la-Poisse, 1981 (Folder 34: 10)
      - Variants, n.d. (Folder 34: 11)
    - Liubimov - Reviews (Box 35)
      - American edition, 1964 (Folder 35: 1)
      - French edition, 1966 (Folder 35: 2)
    - "Liudi i zveri," n.d. (Folder 35: 3)
    - Mysli vrasplokh. Review of French edition, Pensées impromptues, 1968 (Folder 35: 4)
    - "Pamiati pavshikh," n.d. (Folder 35: 5)
    - "Pkhents"
      - Review, 1984 (Folder 35: 6)
      - Translations
        - Danish, in Perspektiv, 1966 (Folder 35: 7)
        - English, in Encounter, 1966 April (Folder 35: 8)
        - French, in Preuves, 1966 April (Folder 35: 9)
        - Portuguese, in Cadernos brasilieros, 1966 May-June. (Folder 35: 10)
          Also includes article by Andrei Siniavskii re Boris Pasternak
    - Progulki s Pushkinym, 1975
      - Proof sheet. Literaturnaia Gazeta, n.d. (Folder 35: 11)
      - Reviews
        - English, 1989-1994 (Folder 35: 12)
        - French, 1976-1977 (Folder 35: 13)
        - Hungarian, 1994 (Folder 35: 14)
      - Stenographic record of dicussion sponsored by Pushkinskaia Komissiia Instituta Mirovoi Literatury AN SSSR, Zhurnal Voprosy Literatury, 1990. (Folder 35: 15)
    - "Rampouch," Czech translation in Svedektvi, 1962. (Folder 35: 16)
    - "Reka i pesnia," 1984. (Folder 35: 17)
    - Spokoinoi nochi: Roman., See also Radio program transcripts/Radio Liberty
      - Holograph draft
        - Chapter 1, "Perevertysh" (Folder 35: 18-20)
        - Chapter 2, "Dom svidanii" (Box-folder 36: 1-8)
        - Chapter 3, "Otets" (Box-folder 37: 1-2)
        - Chapter 4, "Opasnye sviazi" (Folder 37: 3-6)
        - Chapter 5, "Vo chreve kitovym" (Box-folder 38: 1-12)
      - Reviews
        - English edition, Goodnight, 1989 (Folder 39: 1)
        - French edition, Bonne nuit, 1984 (Folder 39: 2)
        - German edition, Gute Nacht, 1985 (Folder 39: 3)
        - Russian edition, Times Literary Supplement, 1985 (Folder 39: 4)
      - Transcript of television interview in German, n.d. (Folder 39: 5)
    - "Sud idet" - Translations
      - Italian, "Si fa il processo," in Tempo presente, 1959 (Folder 39: 6)
      - French, "Citoyens la cour!," in Preuves, 1960. (Folder 39: 7)
      - German, "Der Prozess beginnt," in Der Monat, 1960 (Folder 39: 8)
    - V teni Gogolia. Reviews, 1978 (Folder 39: 9)
    - "Zerkalo," n.d. (Folder 39: 10-14)
    - Miscellany, n.d. (Folder 39: 15)
  - Dissertation reviews, 1979-1984. (Folder 39: 16)
  - Interviews published in periodical press., See also AUDIO-VISUAL FILE/Phonotapes/Siniavskii, Andrei (Box 40)
    - American and British, 1979 (Folder 40: 1)
    - Danish, 1984 (Folder 40: 2)
    - Dutch, 1980-1986., See also PHOTOGRAPHS/Siniavskii, Andrei (Folder 40: 3)
    - French, 1974-1991 (Folder 40: 4-5)
    - German, 1980-1992 (Folder 40: 6)
    - Hungarian, 1980 (Folder 40: 7)
    - Italian, 1975-1991 (Folder 40: 8)
    - Polish, 1984-1993 (Folder 40: 9)
    - Portuguese, 1991 (Folder 40: 10)
    - Swedish, 1987 (Folder 40: 11)
  - Juvenilia., See also EVDOKIIA TORKHOVA-SINIAVSKAIA FILE/ Diaries (Box 41)
    - Drawings and watercolors
      - Notebook, 1931-1932 (Folder 41: 1)
      - Pencil drawings, 1941-1943 (Folder 41: 2)
      - Watercolors, 1938-1942 (Folder 41: 3)
      - Miscellany, 1932 (Folder 41: 4)
    - School notebooks, n.d. (Folder 41: 5-6)
    - Writings. "Zvonok Nos. 1," 1941. (Folder 41: 7)
  - Literary criticism and scholarly articles re Andrei Siniavskii's work., See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Articles about Andrei Siniavskii
    - General
      - General, 1990 (Folder 41: 8)
      - "Forum: The Legacy of Andrei Siniavskii," Slavic and East European Journal, 1998. (Folder 41: 9)
        Galley proof
      - Student writings presented for academic degrees, 1985-1994. (Folder 41: 10-12)
      - Student writings presented for academic degrees, 1985-1994. (Folder 42: 1-2)
    - Brauskova, Marketa, "'Spokoinoi nochi': Ili kuda devalsia Abram Terts'," 1986. (Folder 42: 3)
      Typescript. Includes comments by Siniavskii
    - Durkin, Andrew, "Narrator, Metaphor, and Theme in Sinjavskij's Fantastic Tales," Slavic and East European Journal, 1980 (Folder 42: 4)
    - Gachev, Georgii, "Andrei Siniavskii - Abram Terts i ikh/nii/roman 'Spokoinoi nochi'," n.d. (Folder 42: 5)
    - Genis, Aleksandr and Vail, Petr, "Labardan! Andrei Siniavskii kak Abram Terts," n.d. (Folder 42: 6)
    - Golomshtok, Igor', "Sinyavsky, Andrey," 1993. (Folder 42: 7)
    - Gut, Taja, "Andrej Sinjawskij - Der stilistische Dissident Abram Tertz," Kaspar Hauser, 1964 (Folder 42: 8)
    - Ingold, Felix, "Kunstlertum und Judesein," Zeitschrift für Religions und Geisteschichte, 1976 (Folder 42: 9)
    - Linetskii, Vadim, "Abram Terts: Litso na misheni," 1990. (Folder 42: 10)
    - Matic, Olga, " Spokoinoi noci: Andrei Sinjavskij's Rebirth as Abram Terc," n.d. (Folder 42: 11)
    - Nepomnyashchy, Catherine. Miscellany, n.d. (Folder 42: 12)
      Typescript and printed matter
    - Numano, Mitsuyoshi, "Solzhenitsyn ili Siniavskii!," Inostrannaia Literatura, 1990. (Folder 42: 13)
  - Prison writings
    - Correspondence
      - Rozanova, Mariia
        - 1966
          - February-May (Folder 42: 14)
          - June-July (Folder 42: 15)
          - July-October (Box-folder 43: 1)
          - October-December (Folder 43: 2)
        - 1967
          - January-April (Folder 43: 3)
          - April-July (Folder 43: 4)
          - July-September (Folder 43: 5)
          - September-December (Folder 43: 6)
        - 1968
          - January-March (Folder 43: 7)
          - March-May (Folder 43: 8)
          - May-July (Folder 43: 9)
          - July-October (Folder 43: 10)
          - October-December (Folder 43: 11)
        - 1969
          - January-March (Folder 43: 12)
          - March-June (Folder 43: 13)
          - June-August (Folder 43: 14)
          - August-September (Folder 43: 15)
        - 1970 (Box 44)
          - January-March (Folder 44: 1)
          - April-June (Folder 44: 2)
          - June-July (Folder 44: 3)
          - July-October (Folder 44: 4)
          - October-December (Folder 44: 5)
        - 1971
          - January-February (Folder 44: 6)
          - February-April (Folder 44: 7)
          - April-June (Folder 44: 8)
    - Siniavskii, Egor, 1971 (Folder 44: 9)
  - Loose page and notebooks written in Lefortovo prison and the Mordovian camps.
    Includes material used for Golos iz khora, Progulki s Pushkinym, V teni Gogolia, and Ivan-Durak
    - Loose pages. Numbered by camp authorities (some numbered sections missing)
      - Unnumbered (Folder 44: 10-12)
      - Numbered
        - General
          - Nos. 1-4 (Folder 44: 13)
          - Nos. 6-9 (Folder 44: 14)
          - Nos. 11-13, 15 (Folder 44: 15)
          - Nos. 18-23 (Folder 44: 16)
          - Nos. 26-28, 30-31, 33 (Folder 44: 17)
          - Nos. 34-39, 41, 43, 45-46 (Folder 44: 18)
        - "Poetika drevnei Rusi." Nos. 1-2 (Folder 44: 19)
    - Notebooks (Box 45)
      - "Progulki s Pushkinym." Unnumbered (Folder 45: 1)
      - "Fol'klor"
        - No. 1 (Folder 45: 2)
        - No. 2 (Folder 45: 3)
      - "Umozrenie srednikh vekov"
        - No. 3 (Folder 45: 4)
        - No. 4 (Folder 45: 5)
      - "Gogol'"
        - Unnumbered (Folder 45: 6)
        - No. 5 (Folder 45: 7)
      - "Vyrezki po arkeologii i etnografii." No. 6 (Folder 45: 8)
  - Public lectures., See also OVERSIZE FILE/Posters/Public appearances of Andrei Siniavskii and Mariia Rozanova
    Includes material related to Andrei Siniavskii's participation at conferences and literary events. Arranged chronologically by title.
    - General
      - Notes received from audience at public lectures, n.d. (Folder 46: 1)
      - Announcements and programs for conferences and literary events, 1975-1995 (Folder 46: 2)
    - Untitled speech, the Cathedral of Notre Dame, Paris, n.d. (Folder 46: 3)
    - Untitled speech delivered in honor of Svetlana Gaier, n.d. (Folder 46: 4)
    - Untitled speech re Liubimov, n.d. (Folder 46: 5)
    - "Drevne-russkii khram kak model' vselennoi," the Vatican, n.d. (Folder 46: 6)
      Holograph and typescript
    - "Maiakovskii," lecture delivered at Harvard University, n.d. (Folder 46: 7)
    - "Na raznykh iazykakh," n.d. (Folder 46: 8)
    - "O tsenzure," n.d. (Folder 46: 9)
    - "Vstrechi s zapadom," n.d. (Folder 46: 10)
    - "Vystovka 'Moskva-Parizh'," n.d. (Folder 46: 11)
    - Untitled speech, the Biennale, Venice, 1977. (Folder 46: 12)